WILLIAM WHYTE



Software engineer with 3 years' experience in an Agile environment. Primarily using Pega, a low-code OOP Java platform, to create & deliver applications throughout their lifecycle. Always keen to support and maintain ownership of applications by providing production support and QA when required. Interested in security engineering and completed a PGCert in Cybersecurity in spare time along with being involved in an application security project to automate Pega security checks.

Experience

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - Aflac NI

Jan 2020 - Present

Delivered first applications built from ground-up which automated the process of appeal claims. Responsibilities include:

- Early architecture of projects after analysis of the manual business processes, becoming a SME for the team on how the business/customer operates along with what we need to deliver. Refining, prioritising and tasking user stories for the team backlog based on customer feedback from sprint reviews.
- Developed key functionality along with incorporating non-functional requirements, namely security and usability.
- Worked closely with AppSec; through threat modelling identified application's assets to concentrate on what risks to highlight by applying mitigation controls.
- Encouraged team to apply security best practices throughout our SDLC.
- Delivered items by working independently and through pair-programming for more complex features.
- Overlooked deployment of code throughout environments in each sprint using CI/CD DevOps pipeline.
- Automation of user stories, writing robust unit tests along with UI tests in testing environment.
- Reading log files and debugging when production support is needed.
- Training and mentoring new team members.
- Building relationships with key stakeholders along with presenting and demoing application functionality to them; namely in sprint reviews or when US stakeholders visit the NI office.

Technologies used: Git, Pega, Pega CI/CD Pipelines, Power BI, Python, Robot Framework, Selenium, VS Code

Education

Queen's University, Belfast

Applied Cybersecurity PGCert with Commendation (66)

2021-2022

Technologies used: Burp Suite, C++, Kali Linux, Wireshark

Software Development MSc with Commendation (61)

2018-2019

Technologies used: Eclipse IDE, HTML, CSS, Java, JavaScript, PHP, SQL

History BA Honours (2.1)

2012-2015

IT Certifications

ISTQB - Foundations of Software Testing

2020

Pega - Certified System Architect, Certified Senior System Architect

2020, 2021

Other Work Experience

CUSTOMER SERVICE EXPERIENCE TEAM - W5 Belfast

Aug 2017- Jan 2020

PART-TIME SUPERVISOR / SALES ASSISTANT - Centra NI

Sept 2013- Jun 2017

Working in various departments in customer facing roles. Required a strong grasp of excellent customer satisfaction and dealing with members of public of all ages. Effectively time managed when delegating duties to other members of staff.

Additional Info & Awards

- Passionate about Environmental, Social & Governance (ESG) and became a major role in Aflac NI's 'Green Team' - the team obtained the company the Responsible Plastic Management (RPM) certification
- Interested in reading and learning history; awarded QUB's Certificate in Entrepreneurship Studies and QUB's Mary Gardiner Prize Award (highest distinction in ancient history modules)